const e="We could not find what you asked for, but got you this",o="chemistry",a=200,i=120,t=[{id:27,question:"As the concentration of an electrolyte reduces, the conductivity",option:{a:"Reduces to zero",b:"Decreases",c:"Increases",d:"Is unaffected"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2001"},{id:65,question:"A fixed mass of gas has a  volume of 92cm3 at 30C. What will be be its volume at 180C if the pressure remains constant",option:{a:"15.3cm3",b:"87.3cm3",c:"97.0cm3",d:"552.0cm3"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2002"},{id:269,question:"Elements in the same periodic table have the same",option:{a:"Atomic number",b:"Chemical properties",c:"Physical properties",d:"Number of shells"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:180,question:"When pure aluminum metal is heated to red hot in the presence of nitrogen gas, the compound formed is",option:{a:"AI2N",b:"AIN",c:"AI2N2",d:"AI2N3"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2005"},{id:39,question:"The pair of organic compounds that are isomers is",option:{a:"Benzene and methylbenzene",b:"Trichloromethane and Tetrachloromethane",c:"Ethanol and propanone",d:"But-1-ene and but-2-ene"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2001"},{id:86,question:"The weakest attractive force that can be observed between two molecules is",option:{a:"Ionic",b:"Covalent",c:"Coordinate covalent",d:"Van der Waals"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2003"},{id:87,question:"A consequence of global warming is",option:{a:"Air pollution",b:"Water pollution",c:"Increased humidity",d:"Flooding"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2003"},{id:209,question:"Phenolphthalein in acidic solution is",option:{a:"Colourless",b:"Yellow",c:"Red",d:"Orange"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2005"},{id:81,question:"The noble gases owe their inactivity to",option:{a:"Octet configuration",b:"Cyclic shape",c:"Hexagonal shape",d:"Obtuse configuration"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2003"},{id:301,question:"One of the major uses of Alkanes is",option:{a:"In the hydrogenation of oils",b:"In the textile industries",c:"In the production of plastics",d:"As domestic and industrial fuels"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:194,question:"How many hydrogen atoms does a single ring cycloalkane have less than the corresponding open- chain alkane",option:{a:"Three",b:"One",c:"Four",d:"Two"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2005"},{id:40,question:"A burning candle produces water and",option:{a:"Carbon(II)oxide",b:"Carbon(IV) oxide",c:"Oxygen",d:"Hydrogen"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2001"},{id:120,question:"The process by which atoms are rearranged into different molecular structures in the petroleum refining process is referred to as",option:{a:"Catalytic cracking",b:"Hydrocracking",c:"Polymerization",d:"Reforming"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2003"},{id:227,question:"The order in which a mixture of sand ammonium chloride and sodium chloride can be separated is",option:{a:"Sublimation   dissolution  filtration  evaporation",b:"Dissolution  dryness  filtration  evaporation",c:"Filtration  sublimation  evaporation  dryness",d:"Dissolution  filtration  sublimation  evaporation"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2006"},{id:179,question:"NH4CI(g) ⇌   NH3(g)  +  HCI(g)   The reaction above can only attain equilibrium if",option:{a:"It is in a closed system",b:"It is in an open system",c:"One of the products is removed",d:"A gaseous reactant is added"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2005"},{id:213,question:"Which of the following equimolar solutions will have the highest pH",option:{a:"NH4OH",b:"CH3COONa",c:"HCI",d:"NaOH"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2005"},{id:195,question:"The decolourization of the purple colour of a tetraoxomanganate (VII) ion is a test for",option:{a:"Alkanals",b:"Alkanes",c:"Alkenes",d:"Alkanols"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2005"},{id:193,question:"Equal moles of ethyne and hydrogen iodide react to give",option:{a:"CH2 = CH2",b:"CH2 = CHI",c:"CH2 – CHI",d:"CH2 – CI3"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2005"},{id:43,question:"Which of the followinig respresents hybridization in ethyne?",option:{a:"Sp2",b:"Sp2d",c:"Sp3",d:"sp"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2001"},{id:190,question:"Which of these properties gives a solid its definite shape",option:{a:"Weak intermolecular attraction",b:"High boiling point",c:"High melting point",d:"Strong intermolecular attraction"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2005"},{id:257,question:"Group IA metals are not found free in nature because they",option:{a:"Have high melting and boiling points",b:"Conduct heat and electricity",c:"Are very reactive and unstable",d:"Are malleable and ductile"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2006"},{id:73,question:"The gas that gives brown colouration in brown ring test",option:{a:"Co2",b:"NO2",c:"NO",d:"CO"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2002"},{id:88,question:"Which of the following ions is acidic",option:{a:"K+",b:"NO-3",c:"S2-",d:"H3O+"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2003"},{id:178,question:"The most suitable metal that can be used as a lightening  conductor is",option:{a:"Aluminium",b:"Iron",c:"Copper",d:"Silver"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2005"},{id:187,question:"An element will readily form an electrovalent compound if its electron configuration is",option:{a:"2,8,8",b:"2,,8,4",c:"2,8,5",d:"2,8,1"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2005"},{id:13,question:"What is the decrease in volume of air when pyrogallol is shaken with 30.00cm3 of air",option:{a:"15.00cm3",b:"6.00cm3",c:"0.63cm3",d:"0.06cm3"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2001"},{id:153,question:"Which steam is passed over red-hot carbon, the substances produced are",option:{a:"Hydrogen and trioxocarbonate(IV) acid",b:"Hydrogen, oxygen and carbon(IV) oxide",c:"Hydrogen and carbon (II) oxide",d:"Hydrogen and carbon (IV) oxide"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2004"},{id:61,question:"If 0.75 mole of cyclopropane and 0.66 mole of oxygen are mixed in a vessel with a total pressure of 0.7 atmosphere. What is the partial pressure of oxygen in the mixture",option:{a:"0.55 atmosphere",b:"0.44 atmosphere",c:"0.33 atmosphere",d:"0.22 atmosphere"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2002"},{id:281,question:"The IUPAC nomencalatyre of the compound LiAIH4 is",option:{a:"Aluminium tetrahydrido lithium",b:"Tetrahydrido lithium aluminate (III)",c:"Lithium aluminium hydride",d:"Lithium tetrahydridoaluminate (III)"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:117,question:"The type of reaction that is peculiar to benzene is",option:{a:"Addition",b:"Hydrolysis",c:"Polymerization",d:"Substitution"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2003"},{id:298,question:"Which of the following is used to hasten the ripening of fruit",option:{a:"Ethanol",b:"Ethyne",c:"Ethane",d:"Ethane"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:199,question:"The enzyme responsible for converting sucrose into two simple isomeric sugars is",option:{a:"Invertase",b:"Amylase",c:"Lactose",d:"Maltase"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2005"},{id:142,question:"The oxidation state of chlorine in HClO4 is",option:{a:"-5",b:"-1",c:"1",d:"7"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2004"},{id:122,question:"the principal constituent of natural gas is methane",option:{a:"ethane",b:"propane",c:"butane",d:"butane"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2003"},{id:203,question:"The solubility curve shows the variation of solute concentration with",option:{a:"Volume",b:"Vapour density",c:"Pressure",d:"Temperature"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2005"},{id:133,question:"Chlorine consisting of two isotopes of mass numbers 35 and 37 in the ratio 3:1 has an atomic mass of 35.5. Calculate the relative abundance of the isotope of mass number 37.",option:{a:"20",b:"25",c:"60",d:"75"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2004"},{id:151,question:"The allotrope of carbon used in the decolourization of sugar is",option:{a:"Graphite",b:"Soot",c:"Charcoal",d:"Lampblack"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2004"},{id:21,question:"What current in amperes will deposit 2.7g of aluminium in 2 hours [Al = 27, f = 96500 C mol-1]",option:{a:"32",b:"8",c:"4",d:"16"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2001"},{id:158,question:"Transition metals posses variable oxidation states because they have",option:{a:"Electrons in the d orbitals",b:"Electrons in the s orbitals",c:"A variable number of electrons in the p orbitals",d:"Partially filled p orbitals"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2004"},{id:196,question:"In the purification of impure samples of ethyl ethanoate synthesized by esterification, concentrated sodium trioxocarbonate(IV) solution is used to remove",option:{a:"Water",b:"Acidic impurities",c:"Basic impurities",d:"Ethoxyethane"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2005"},{id:41,question:"The gas that can best be collected by downward displacement of air is",option:{a:"Chlorine",b:"Sulphur(IV)oxide",c:"Ammonia",d:"Carbon(IV)oxide"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2001"},{id:64,question:"A gas X diffuses twice as fast as gas Y under the same conditions. If the relative molecular mass of X is 28. Calculate the relative molecular mass of Y",option:{a:"120",b:"14",c:"56",d:"112"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2002"},{id:28,question:"In which of the following reactions has the oxidation number of nitrogen increased",option:{a:"2NO(g)  +  Br2(l)  → 2NOBr(l)",b:"2NO2(g)  +  O2(g)   → 2NO2(g)",c:"FeSO4(aq)  +  NO(g) → Fe(NO)SO4(s)",d:"2NO(g)  +  CI2(g) →  2NOCI(l)"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2001"},{id:115,question:"The leachate of a certain plant ash is used in local soap making because it contains",option:{a:"Sodium chloride and potassium hydroxide",b:"Sodium hydroxide",c:"Potassium hydroxide",d:"Soluble carbonates and hydrogen carbonates"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2003"},{id:183,question:"What is the valence shell electron configuration of the element with atomic number 17",option:{a:"1s22s22p63s23p5",b:"1s22s22p63s23p4",c:"3s23p5",d:"2s22p6"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2005"},{id:300,question:"The correct order of increasing boiling points of the following  compounds C3H7OH, C7H16 and C4H10 is",option:{a:"C4H10  →  C7H16 → C3H7OH",b:"C7H16 → C3H7OH → C4H16",c:"C4H10  → C3H7OH  → C4H10",d:"C3H7OH →  C4H10  → C7H16"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:280,question:"6AgNO3(aq)  +  PH3(g) +    3H2O(l)      →    6Ag(s)+   H3PO3(aq)   +    6HNO3(aq)  In the reaction above, the reducing agent is",option:{a:"H2O(l)",b:"PH3(g)",c:"AgNO3(aq)",d:"HNO3(AQ)"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:140,question:"Which of these compounds is a normal salt",option:{a:"NaHS",b:"NaSO4",c:"NaHCO3",d:"Na2CO3"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2004"},{id:134,question:"Which of the following mixtures of gases is likely to burn in flame",option:{a:"Neon and hydrogen",b:"Nitrogen and helium",c:"Helium and neon",d:"Neon and nitrogen"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2004"},{id:284,question:"In which of the following is the entropy change positive",option:{a:"Reaction between an acid and a base",b:"Addition of concentrated acid to water",c:"Dissolution of sodium metal in water",d:"Thermal dissociation of ammonium chloride"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:78,question:"The filter in a cigarette reduces the nicotine content by",option:{a:"Burning",b:"Adsorption",c:"Evaporation",d:"Absorption"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2003"},{id:275,question:"Carbon (II) oxide is considered dangerous if inhaled mainly because it",option:{a:"Competes with oxygen in the blood",b:"Competes with carbon (IV) oxide in the blood",c:"Can cause lung cancer",d:"Can cause injury to the nervous system"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:84,question:"A gas exerts pressure on its container because",option:{a:"Some of its molecules are moving faster than others",b:"Of the collision of the molecules with each other",c:"Of the mass of the molecules of gas",d:"The molecules of a gas collide with the walls of the container"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2003"},{id:105,question:"Metals of the first transition series have special proper ties which are different from those of groups I and II elements because they have partially filled",option:{a:"s  orbitals",b:"p orbitals",c:"d orbitals",d:"f orbitals"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2003"},{id:271,question:"Permanent hardness of water can be removed by",option:{a:"Adding slaked lime",b:"Adding caustic soda",c:"Boiling",d:"Filtration"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:246,question:"Which of the following results in the fall of acid rain",option:{a:"Gaseous hydrocarbons",b:"Oxide of lead",c:"Particulate matter",d:"Oxides of sulphur"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2006"},{id:208,question:"A concentrated solution containing H+, Cu2+, OH- and Cl- was electrolyzed using platinum electrodes. The ion that will be discharged at the cathode is",option:{a:"OH-",b:"Cl-",c:"Cu2+",d:"H+"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2005"},{id:166,question:"The reaction above is",option:{a:"Carboxylation",b:"Decarboxylation",c:"Acidification",d:"Esterification"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2004"},{id:75,question:"What volume of oxygen is produced from the decomposition of 2 moles of KClO3 at s.t.p   [Molar volume of a gas at s.t.p = 22.4 dm3]",option:{a:"22.4 dm3",b:"33.6 dm3",c:"44.8 dm3",d:"67.2 dm3"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2003"},{id:211,question:"What is the correct IUPAC name for NO2",option:{a:"Dioxonitrate(III) ion",b:"Dioxonitrate(IV) ION",c:"trioxonitrate(iii) ion",d:"trioxonitrate(iv) ion"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2005"},{id:215,question:"Which of the following ions requires the largest quantity of electricity for discharge at an electrode",option:{a:"2.5 moles of Cu2+",b:"4.0 moles of CI-",c:"2.0 moles of Al3+",d:"3.0 moles of Na+"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2005"},{id:237,question:"Which of the following has an isomer",option:{a:"C4H10",b:"C6H6",c:"C2H4",d:"C2H6"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2006"},{id:35,question:"A trihydric alkanol is",option:{a:"glycerol",b:"phenol",c:"glycol",d:"ethanol"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2001"},{id:63,question:"Which of the following statements is true of a proton.",option:{a:"The total mass of the protons in a particular nucleus always half the nuclear mass",b:"The mass of a proton is 1840 times the mass of an electron",c:"The mass proton is 1.0008g",d:"The mass of a proton is one-twelfth the molar mass of carbon"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2002"},{id:260,question:"Which of he following pairs of substances will react further with oxygen to form a higher oxide",option:{a:"SO2 and NO",b:"CO2 and H2O",c:"CO and CO2",d:"NO and H2O"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2006"},{id:102,question:"When sugar is dissolved in tea, the reaction is always accompanied by",option:{a:"Positive entropy change",b:"Negative entropy change",c:"No entropy change",d:"A minimum entropy change"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2003"},{id:89,question:"The structural component that makes detergent dissolve more quickly in water than soap is",option:{a:"–SO3 –Na+",b:"–COO-Na+",c:"–SO4- Na+",d:"–COO-K+"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2003"},{id:150,question:"Which of the following shows little or no net reaction when the volume of the system is decreased",option:{a:" H2(g)  +  l2(g)  ⇌  2Hl(g)",b:"2NO2(g)  ⇌  N2O4(g)",c:" PCl5(g)   ⇌ PCl3(g)  + Cl2(g)",d:" 203(g)   ⇌  3O2(g)"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2004"},{id:184,question:"A heterogeneous mixture can be defined as any mixture",option:{a:"Whose composition is uniform",b:"Whose composition is not uniform",c:"Formed by solids and liquids",d:"Of a solute and a solvent"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2005"},{id:20,question:"Which of the following best explains the increase in the rate of a chemical reaction as the temperature rises",option:{a:"The bonds in the reacting molecules are more readily broken",b:"The molecules collisions become more violent",c:"A lower proportion of the molecules has the necessary minimum energy to react",d:"The collision frequency of the molecules increases"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2001"},{id:162,question:"An isomer of C5H12 is",option:{a:"Butane",b:"2-methylbutane",c:"2-methylprpane",d:"2-ethylbutane"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2004"},{id:156,question:"Aluminium hydroxide is used in the dyeing industry as a",option:{a:"Salt",b:"Dye",c:"Mordant",d:"Dispersant"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2004"},{id:121,question:"Which of the following is found in cotton",option:{a:"Starch",b:"Cellulose",c:"fat",d:"oil"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2003"},{id:163,question:"A characteristic of the alkane family is",option:{a:"Addition reaction",b:"Elimination reaction",c:"Substitution reaction",d:"Neutralization reaction"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2004"},{id:37,question:"Proteins in acid solution undergo",option:{a:"Polymerization",b:"Substitution",c:"Fermentation",d:"Hydrolysis"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2001"},{id:100,question:"In the electrolysis of a concentrated solution of sodium chloride using inert electrodes, which of the following ions are discharged at the cathode and anode respectively",option:{a:"Na+ and Cl-",b:"Na+ and OH-",c:"H+ and OH-",d:"H+ and Cl-"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2003"},{id:287,question:"2H2(g) +    O2(g)  ⇌ 2H2O(g)    ΔH   =  - ve  What happens to the equilibrium constant of the reaction above if the temperature is increased?",option:{a:"It becomes zero",b:"It decreases",c:"It increases",d:"It is unaffected"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:18,question:"P(g) + O(g)    ⇌ 3R(s)  +  S(g)   ΔH is negative which of the following will increase the yield of R",option:{a:"Using a larger closed vessel",b:"Increasing the temperature",c:"Removing some S",d:"Adding a positive catalyst"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2001"},{id:155,question:"Carbon is tetravalent because",option:{a:"The electrons in both the 2s and 2p orbitals are equivalent",b:"The electrons in all the orbitals of carbon are equivalent",c:"The 2s and 2p atomic orbitals hybridize",d:"All the atomic orbitals of carbon hybridize"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2004"},{id:131,question:"The shape of the s-orbital is",option:{a:"Spherical",b:"Elliptical",c:"Spiral",d:"Circular"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2004"},{id:170,question:"The property used in the industrial preparation of nitrogen and oxygen from air is",option:{a:"Rate of diffusion",b:"Solubility",c:"Density",d:"Boiling point"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2005"},{id:1,question:"25cm3 of a gas X contains Zmolecules at 150C and 75mmHg. How many molecules will 25cmm3 of another gas Y contain at the same temperature and pressure",option:{a:"2Y",b:"2Z",c:"Z",d:"Y"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2001"},{id:304,question:"The compound that is used as an anaesthetic is",option:{a:"CHCI3",b:"CH2C2",c:"CH3CI",d:"CCI4"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:264,question:"The volume of a gas is Vcm3 at P mm Hg. What is the new volume of the gas if the pressure is reduced to half at constant temperature",option:{a:"2 V cm3",b:"V  2cm3",c:"V cm3",d:"4 V cm3"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:11,question:"Deliquenscent substances are used for",option:{a:"Cooling",b:"Wetting",c:"Melting",d:"Drying"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2001"},{id:245,question:"When 5.0cm3 of a saturated solution of sugar of molar mass 342g at 400C was evaporated to dryness, 34.2g of dry solid was obtained. The solubility of sugar at 400C is",option:{a:"7.0 mol dm-3",b:"3.5 mol dm-3",c:"2.0 mol dm-3",d:"10.0mol dm-3"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2006"},{id:112,question:"Ethene reacts with hydrogen bromide to give",option:{a:"CH2Br2",b:"CH3CH2Br",c:"C2H2Br2",d:"CHBr3"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2003"},{id:290,question:"A constituent common to moist air, it gradually rusts. This is due to the formation of",option:{a:"Silver",b:"Copper",c:"Tin",d:"Lead"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:62,question:"The processes which return carbon(IV) oxide to the atmosphere include",option:{a:"Photosynthesis, decay and respiration",b:"Photosynthesis, respiration and transpiration",c:"Respiration, decay and combustion",d:"Ozone, depletion, combustion and decay"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2002"},{id:98,question:"If Y is an oxidizing agent that reacts with a reducing agent, Z, which of the following is correct",option:{a:"Y increases in oxidation number",b:"Y becomes reduced",c:"Z loses protons",d:"Z gains protons"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2003"},{id:274,question:"Coffee stains can best be removed by",option:{a:"Turpentine",b:"A solution of borax in water",c:"Ammonia solution",d:"Kerosene"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:116,question:"The formula for ethyl butanoate is",option:{a:"C3H7COOC2H5",b:"C2H5COOC3H7",c:"C4H9COOC2H5",d:"C2H5COOC4H9"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2003"},{id:124,question:"A chemical reaction is always associated with",option:{a:"An increase in the composition of one of the substances",b:"A change in the volume of the reactants",c:"A change in the nature of the reactants",d:"The formation of new substances"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2004"},{id:16,question:"Phosphorous is stored under water to precvent it from",option:{a:"Dehydrating",b:"Becoming inert",c:"Smelling",d:"Catching fire"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2001"},{id:238,question:"An example of aliphatic unsaturated hydrocarbon is",option:{a:"Butanol",b:"Propene",c:"Pentane",d:"Benzene"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2006"},{id:191,question:"The component of an atom that contributes least to its mass is the",option:{a:"Nucleus",b:"Neutron",c:"Electron",d:"Proton"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2005"},{id:189,question:"The shape of the hydrocarbon compound CH4 is",option:{a:"Square planar",b:"Tetrahedral",c:"Planar",d:"Linear"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2005"},{id:220,question:"Trioxonitrate(V) acid is not used for preparing hydrogen gas from metals because it",option:{a:"Renders the metal passive",b:"Is strongly oxidizing",c:"Is volatile",d:""},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2006"},{id:32,question:"The main impurity in iron ore during the extraction of iron is",option:{a:"Silicon (IV) oxide",b:"Carbon(IV) oxide",c:"Calciumtrioxosilicate",d:"Sulphur(II) oxide"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2001"},{id:119,question:"A compound contains 40.0% carbon, 6.7% hydrogen and 53.3% oxygen. If the molar mass of the compound is 180, find the molecular formula  [H = 1, C = 12, O = 16]",option:{a:"CH2O",b:"C3H6O3",c:"C6H12O6",d:"C6H6O3"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2003"},{id:143,question:"ZnO(s) + CO (g) → Zn(s) + CO2 (g). ",option:{a:"Decomposed",b:"Displaced",c:"Oxidized",d:"Reduced"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2004"},{id:288,question:"To a solution of an unknown compound, a little dilute Tetraoxosulphate (IV) acid was added with some freshly prepared (II) Tetraoxosulphate (VI) Solution. The brown ring observed after the addition of a stream of concentrated  Tetraoxosulphate (VI) acid confirmed the presence of",option:{a:"CI",b:"SO",c:"NO",d:"CO"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:125,question:"If a solution contains 4.8g of Tetraoxosulphate (VI) acid. Calculate the amount of copper(II) oxide that will react with it  [CU = 64, O = 16, S = 32, H = 1]",option:{a:"0.8g",b:"4.0g",c:"40.0g",d:"80.0g"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2004"},{id:223,question:"IN which of the following is the oxidation number of sulphur equal to -2",option:{a:"H2S",b:"SO3",c:"S8",d:"SO2"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2006"},{id:139,question:"Calcium Tetraoxosulphate(VI) dissolves in water only sparingly to form a",option:{a:"Solution",b:"Suspension",c:"Precipitate",d:"Colloid"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2004"},{id:144,question:"Which of the following acts as both a reducing and an oxidizing agent",option:{a:"H2",b:"SO2",c:"H2S",d:"CO2"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2004"},{id:248,question:"An emulsion may be produced by shaking a detergent solution with",option:{a:"Palm wine",b:"Palm oil",c:"Ethanoic acid",d:"Water"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2006"},{id:49,question:"The chromatographic separation of ink is based on the ability of the components to",option:{a:"React with each other",b:"React with the solvent",c:"Dissolve in each other in the column",d:"Move at different speeds in the column"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2002"},{id:293,question:"Stainless steel is used for making",option:{a:"Tools",b:"Coins and medals",c:"Moving parts of clocks",d:"Magnets"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:54,question:"The furring of kettles is caused by the presence in water of",option:{a:"Calcium trioxocarbonate(IV)",b:"Calcium tetraoxosulphate(VI)",c:"CALCIUM HYDROXIDE",d:"Calcium hydrofentrioxocarbonate(IV)"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2002"},{id:38,question:"A characteristic reaction of the compounds with the general formula CnH2n is",option:{a:"Esterification",b:"Polymerization",c:"Decarboxylation",d:"Substitution"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2001"},{id:55,question:"Tetraoxosulphate(VI) acid burns the skin by",option:{a:"Heating",b:"Hydration",c:"Dehydration",d:"Hydrolysis"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2002"},{id:157,question:"Alloys are best prepared by",option:{a:"Electroplating",b:"Arc-welding",c:"Reducing a mixture of their metallic oxides",d:"Cooling a molten mixture of the metals"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2004"},{id:168,question:"In the production of soap, concentrated sodium chloride solution is added to",option:{a:"Increase the solubility of the soap",b:"Decrease the solubility of the soap",c:"Saponify the soap",d:"Emulsify the soap"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2004"},{id:218,question:"The ion that can be used as an oxidizing agent is",option:{a:"Fe3+",b:"F-",c:"Ca2+",d:"Au3+"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2006"},{id:228,question:"The volume of 2.5 moles of oxygen at s.t.p is",option:{a:"56.0dm3",b:"84.0dm3",c:"50.0dm3",d:"20.0dm3"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2006"},{id:14,question:"Environmental pollution is worsened by the release from automobile exhausts of",option:{a:"Water vapour",b:"Steam",c:"Smoke",d:"Heavy metals"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2001"},{id:292,question:"A compound gives an orange red colour to a non luminous flame. This compound is likely to contain",option:{a:"Ca2+",b:"Fe3+",c:"Fe2+",d:"Na+"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:252,question:"Carbon exists naturally in the combined state as",option:{a:"Diamond",b:"Coal",c:"Wood",d:"Graphite"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2006"},{id:68,question:"A rock sample was added to cold dilute HNMO3. The gas evolved was passed into a solution of acidified K2Cr2O7 and the solution turned green. The rock sample contains",option:{a:"NO3-",b:"Cl-",c:"SO42-",d:"SO32-"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2002"}],n={message:e,subject:o,status:200,total:120,data:t};export{t as data,n as default,e as message,a as status,o as subject,i as total};
